GUSTAVO DIEFENBACH

Mobile Developer | SwiftUI | UIKit | Flutter | Games

Floresta / Porto Alegre, Rio Grande do Sul, Brasil

Phone: +55 051 991301412

Email: gustavodiefenbach@gmail.com

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/gstvdfnbch/

GitHub: https://github.com/gstvdfnbch Medium:https://medium.com/@gstvdfnbch

PROFESSIONAL OBJECTIVE

To contribute to the innovative development of digital products and solutions, applying creativity in process organization and suggesting improvements in user experience. Aiming to play a crucial role in creating engaging and memorable products, focusing on enhancing user satisfaction and entertainment.

EDUCATION

(2015 - Present) Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul Electrical Engineering

(2010 - 2014) Liberato Salzano Vieira da Cunha Technical School Foundation Electronic Technician

WORK EXPERIENCE

(01/2024 - Present) iOS Developer: Developing a mobile app for iPhone in Swift using SwiftUI.

(03/2023 - Present) iOS Developer, Apple Developer Academy - PUCRS: Explored Apple resources including SpriteKit, GameController, SwiftUI, UIKit, CoreGraphics, AVFoundation, and haptics.

(01/2022 - Present) Flutter Developer - Freelancer: Developing a mobile app in Flutter called Encarte Rápido, compatible with both iOS and Android platforms. The app generates supermarket flyers for advertising promotions.

(11/2021 - 05/2023) Project Assistant, PONFAC S.A: Worked with developed products that used computer vision and neural networks. Tasks carried out included equipment maintenance, product and prototype assembly, part design, and validation testing of parts and products.

(06/2018 - 11/2021) Electronics Technician, Hydraulic Works Laboratory - LOH / UFRGS

(01/2014 - 06/2015) Jr. Programmer - C Language, Pro Tune Electronic Systems.

CERTIFICATES

English:

(2019) English Oxford University 5 – Advanced Level

(2018) English Oxford University 4 – Upper Intermediate Level

Courses:

(2024 - In progress) Unreal Engine 5 C++ Developer (Udemy)

(2019) Flutter and Dart Course (Udemy)

(2019) Python Course (Udemy)

Entrepreneur events:

(2023) Tecnopuc StartUp Garage with Encarte Fácil App - Finalist

Workshop:

(2023) Core NFC Framework (Apple Developer Academy)

Scientific Initiation Exhibition:

(2020) Calibrator for air concentration meters in water (UFRGS)

(2019) Dynamic analysis in a three-dimensional environment (UFRGS) (2018) Use of capacitors for pressure measurement in piezometers (UFRGS)

KNOWLEDGES

Main knowledges: Swift | SwiftUI | UIKit | Dart | Flutter

<u>Secondary knowledges:</u> C | Python | AdMob | UXCam | Photoshop | SpriteKit | SceneKit | Illustrator | GameplayKit | Figma | GameCenter | Pro Create

PROJECTS

Encarte Rápido - Flutter | API

Encarte Rápido is an app that streamlines leaflet creation for small and medium-sized Brazilian supermarkets. Replaces slow, costly services with a quick, affordable option, simplifying marketing.

Managed app with 250 paying clients, generating 1800 leaflet, 80% from paying clients.

Play Store: https://bit.ly/43yjReZ | App Store: https://apple.co/4arn3LM

Flipty: Where decision roll - Swift | SceneKit | Haptics | Watch Kit | Voice Over | Core Motion Developed an app for Apple Watch and iPhone with a six-sided dice game and a Head and Tails game, activated by gesture detection. Rotate your wrist to spin the dice, or make a throwing motion to flip the virtual coin.

App hit top 3 on launch day and stayed top 10 for board games on App Store for a week.

App Store: https://apple.co/4aUm33n

Burguer Maker - Swift | SpriteKit | AVFoundation | AdMob | Design

My first independent game, a burger maker simulator where difficulty scales with your score.

App Store: https://apple.co/3TzWM7b

Tans: Logic for Kids - Swift | SwiftUI | Haptics

Educational application focused on logical reasoning and computational thinking for children aged 7 to 9, developed using SwiftUI.

App Store: https://apple.co/3PS3swO